NATHALY **SEGURA SANCHEZ**

348 Weber St W **1** (416) 6024328

www.linkedin.com/in/nathaly-segura-

sanchez in



PROFESIONAL SUMMARY

Effective and passionate Business Intelligence Analyst with 5+ of experience executing data-driven solutions to raise profits, decrease expenses, enhance customer relationships, lower risks, and more. Proficient knowledge in Information Technology, Statistics, Mathematics, and Analytics. Experienced at creating descriptive and predictive data mining models, using Machine learning algorithms to deliver insights and implement action-oriented solutions to complex business problems. I have worked in different stages of data-based projects, from the extraction, transformation and loading of data to the analysis, interpretation, and presentation of the results to the organization which has armed me with critical thinking.



EDUCATION

Business Analytics Post-Graduate Certificate | Conestoga College SEPTEMBER 2023 – ABRIL 2024

Predictive Analytics Post-Graduate Certificate | Conestoga College SEPTEMBER 2022 – ABRIL 2023

Master's in Architecture for Information Technology | Andes University NOVEMBER 2013 – OCTOBER 2015

Systems Engineer bachelor's degree (Computer Science) | Distrital University JUNE 2005 – OCTOBER 2011



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics | Cirka | Melbourne, AustraliaJUNE 2021 – JUNE 2022

- Developed efficient methods of gathering and cleaning data for different projects.
- Developed multi-table SQL procedures to extract information to create different analysis.
- Designed and created dashboards and automated reporting to provide actionable insights.
- Collaborated in the gathering of requirements from end users and translating them into functional/technical design of reports or applications.
- Identified, developed, and implemented automated workflows and processes, scripts, and other tools such as in-house databases to streamline repetitive tasks.

Data Specialist | Alcaldia Mayor de Bogota (Mayor's office) | Bogota, Colombia JULY 2017 – JANUARY 2020

- Supported the identification and evaluation of requirements based organizational missionary processes in terms of business intelligence.
- Designed, implemented, and validated all stages necessary for the construction of Data Mining Models that allow decision making strategies based on predictive analytics models.
- Created reports and visualizations through data analysis that help solve business problems using SQL and tuning analytic queries.
- Executed queries databases to gather data from various sources.

- Participated in troubleshooting and problem analysis and solution.
- Handled large data files for loading and/or reconciliation/data manipulation.
- Worked with business analysts to construct mock-ups, and in an Agile development process created reports.

Data Specialist – Junior Actuary Reserving | AXA Colpatria | Bogota, Colombia OCTOBER 2012 – OCTOBER 2016

- Communicated findings in written and oral formats with both internal and external stakeholders, including upper management.
- Designed and implemented a data mining project that allows the Actuary area and other user areas to make business decisions.
- Translate pricing business problems into advanced solutions by developing data models and assets, experimenting with innovative ideas.

Development Engineer | Bits Americas | Bogota, ColombiaSEPTEMBER 2009 – SEPTEMBER 2012

- Defined the product functional analysis (based on standard) to translate customer specifications and internal requirements into clear product performance criteria.
- Completed software development life cycle from requirements to design, implementation, testing and release.
- Designed and created reports for clients to allow making business decisions.



SKILLS

- In-depth experience using BI Tools (Power BI, DAX, Tableau, Excel).
- Proficiency with R and Python.
- Experience writing SQL and T-SQL queries and relational database structure.
- Proficiency in data management tools and databases.
- Understanding of data governance principles, data privacy regulations, and best practices for ensuring data security and confidentiality.

- Experience in developing and implementing automated workflows.
- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Familiarity with CRM systems and data integration platforms.
- Ability to effectively manage multiple projects.
- Willingness to learn and adapt to evolving technologies.
- Strong interpersonal skills.



TRAINING

Data Science training and certification | Melbourne | Australia - 2022 Citizen Data Scientist training and certification | Bogota | Colombia - 2018 Data mining training | Bogota | Colombia - 2017 Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) | Bogota | Colombia - 2012